Register of the Chinese subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- 2015 Incremental Materials, 1966-1976
  - DAZIBAO big character poster (大字报), 1966-1976 (Oversize scrolls 1-4)
    The big character poster titled, "Some Complaints about the Leaders of the Ministry," was created by the staff of the Thirteenth Bureau under the Chinese Ministry of Public Security during China's Cultural Revolution (1966-1976). The Thirteenth Bureau was in charge of Qincheng Prison, China's maximum-security political prison, that incarcerated previously influential political figures. During the Cultural Revolution, there was vehement factional fighting in the Thirteenth Bureau.
    大字报作者为中华人民共和国公安部下属的十三局的员工。十三局即公安部下属的预审局，负责管理专门关押中华人民共和国高级官员的秦城监狱。文化大革命期间，公安部十三局两派斗争激烈。
    The series is composed of a four-part poster in which the staff of the Thirteenth Bureau, under Chinese Ministry of Public Security, expressed their discontent with their leaders, criticizing them as being arbitrary and suppressing democracy. Sun Pengfei, the vice director of the Bureau, was mentioned in the poster as being inefficient in promoting the Cultural Revolution within the Bureau. In addition, the authors considered the leaders of the Ministry of Public Security to be failures in listening to the voices of the ordinary staff in the Thirteenth Bureau and thus advocated that leaders to visit the Bureau more often. In the last section of the poster, the signatures of the 33 staff members of the Thirteenth Bureau are evident.
    该大字报共有四页，根据内容推测创作于中国文化大革命（1966－1976）时期。该大字报主要表达了中华人民共和国公安部下属的十三局员工对领导阶层的不满，认为局领导专横无礼、压制民主。其中，十三局副局长孙鹏飞被点名批评。同时，该大字报认为公安部高层对十三局重视不够，导致文化大革命在局内无法彻底进行。大字报中要求公安部领导对十三局领导加以监管，并且多聆听群众呼声。